export const QUIZ_DATA = [
  {
    question:
      "Is fermentation the process of converting grape sugar into alcohol?",
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Fermentation is the process of converting grape sugar into alcohol, carbon dioxide, and other byproducts through the action of yeast.",
  },
  {
    question: 'Is "sur lie" aging a technique where wine is aged on its lees?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      '"Sur lie" aging is a technique where wine is aged on its lees (dead yeast cells) to enhance its complexity and mouthfeel.',
  },
  {
    question:
      "Is maceration the process of soaking grape skins and solids in wine to extract color, tannins, and flavors?",
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Maceration is the process of soaking grape skins and solids in wine to extract color, tannins, and flavors.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "blending" the process of mixing wines from different grape varieties or vintages?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Blending is the process of mixing wines from different grape varieties or vintages to achieve a desired flavor profile or balance.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "malolactic fermentation" a process that converts malic acid to lactic acid, reducing acidity in wine?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Malolactic fermentation is a process that converts malic acid to lactic acid, reducing acidity and giving a smoother mouthfeel to wine.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "decanting" the process of pouring wine into a separate container to remove sediment and aerate the wine?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Decanting is the process of pouring wine into a separate container to remove sediment and aerate the wine, improving its flavor and aroma.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "corked" a term used to describe a wine that has been contaminated by cork taint?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Corked is a term used to describe a wine that has been contaminated by cork taint, which can cause off-flavors and aromas.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "fortified wine" a type of wine that has been strengthened with the addition of a distilled spirit, such as brandy?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Fortified wine is a type of wine that has been strengthened with the addition of a distilled spirit, such as brandy. Examples include Port, Sherry, and Madeira.",
  },
  {
    question: 'Is "punt" the indentation found on the bottom of a wine bottle?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Punt is the term for the indentation found on the bottom of a wine bottle, which can provide stability and help distribute sediment.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "oak aging" a process of aging wine in oak barrels to impart flavors and tannins?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Oak aging is a process of aging wine in oak barrels to impart flavors, such as vanilla or spice, and tannins to the wine.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "appellation" a legally defined geographical area for wine production?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "An appellation is a legally defined geographical area for wine production, which can dictate the grape varieties and production methods used.",
  },
  {
    question: 'Is "brix" a scale used to measure the sugar content in grapes?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Brix is a scale used to measure the sugar content in grapes, which can help determine the potential alcohol content of the resulting wine.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "residual sugar" the sugar content remaining in a wine after fermentation is complete?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Residual sugar refers to the sugar content remaining in a wine after fermentation is complete, which can influence the sweetness of a wine.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "Old World" a term used to describe wines from traditional wine-producing regions, such as Europe?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Old World is a term used to describe wines from traditional wine-producing regions, such as Europe, where wine production has a long history.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Is "New World" a term used to describe wines from newer wine-producing regions, such as the United States, Australia, and South America?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["True", "False"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "New World is a term used to describe wines from newer wine-producing regions, such as the United States, Australia, and South America, where wine production may be more innovative.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the standard size for a bottle of wine?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["500ml", "750ml","800ml"],
    correctAnswer: "1",
    explanation:
      "Most wine is sold in 750ml bottles.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the size of a magnum bottle?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["1 liter", "1.25 liters","1.5 liters"],
    correctAnswer: "2",
    explanation:
      "A magnum bottle of wine is the equivalent of 2 standard bottles.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who is the patron saint of winemakers?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["Saint Lawrence", "Saint Honore","Saint Vincent"],
    correctAnswer: "2",
    explanation:
      "Celebrated every January 22, Saint Vincent is the patron saint of winemakers and he symbolizes the solidarity among them.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'In what country did the phylloxera insect originate?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["United States", "France","Italy"],
    correctAnswer: "0",
    explanation:
      "Grape phylloxera is an insect pest of commercial grapevines, originally native to eastern North America. In the late 19th century the phylloxera epidemic destroyed most of the vineyards in Europe, especially in France.",
  },
  {
    question:
      'What is the name of the pest that caused the epidemic that destroyed most of the vineyards for wine grapes in Europe in the late 19th century?',
    questionType: "multiplechoice",
    answerSelectionType: "single",
    answers: ["botrytis", "phylloxera","brettanomyces"],
    correctAnswer: "1",
    explanation:
      "In the late 19th century the phylloxera epidemic destroyed most of the vineyards for wine grapes in Europe. It was introduced to Europe when botanists collected specimens of American vines in the 1850s.",
  },
];
